Tim Perry

□ pimterry@gmail.com

British

Based in Barcelona

% Tim.FYI

@pimterry

github.com/pimterry

stackoverflow.com/users/68051

I'm a passionate and accomplished **tech lead**, **full-stack developer**, and **technical speaker**, with a history of delivering successful projects in every technology and environment I can find.

I'm particularly focused on **web applications**, **HTTP**, **JavaScript** and **Java**, but with a wide range of professional experience in other domains and technologies, from Android to C# to CouchDB. I've proven myself effective planning large & complex projects, leading distributed teams, developing within such teams, and single-handedly taking projects from concept to delivery.

I'm also an enthusiastic **open-source maintainer and contributor**, with a long list of open-source contributions and projects of my own, along with other side projects.

Experience

Creator - HTTP Toolkit

Since November 2018

Creator of a solo bootstrapped open-source business, building a developer tool for HTTP(S) interception, inspecting & rewriting.

Built into a successful business single-handedly, including all design, development & marketing. See <u>HttpToolkit.tech</u> for details.

HTTP, TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, Electron

Senior Software Developer - Balena

December 2016 - November 2018

Senior developer in an early stage startup building an open-core IoT deployment platform. Lead maintainer of the SDK & CLI, and major contributor to the web dashboard & API. Lead the project to move user billing from a fully manual process to a fully automated self-serve system, boosting ARR by 20% overnight at launch.

TypeScript, IoT, API/SDK/CLI design, billing infrastructure, Postgres

Developer Outreach & Oversight - Softwire

June 2015 - November 2016

Gave technical talks at conferences worldwide, created & drove the internal open-source program, wrote technical articles, and encouraged others in this company-wide.

Internally managed & supported project technical leads throughout the company on technical & management challenges.

Public speaking, technical writing, management, training

Education

University of Oxford

2007 - 2011

Masters in Computer Science, 2:1

Open-source projects

Loglevel

2.000

https://git.io/v6TPL

Lightweight ultra-reliable logging tool for safe cross-browser JS.

Installed from NPM around 10 million times a week.

JavaScript, Node.js, logging.

Notes

947 🚖

https://git.io/JYBfY

Note-taking CLI tool, designed with to fit the Unix philosophy with zero lock-in.

Bash, BATS, Unix design.

Mockttp

347 🚖

https://git.io/JvnZL

HTTP(S) inspection & rewriting JS proxy for browser and Node.js HTTP testing, and automated capture and rewriting.

TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, HTTP.

Experience (continued)

Tech lead, BBC Newsbeat - Softwire

December 2014 - April 2015

Technical lead for rewrite of BBC Newsbeat as a responsive site with Android & iOS apps, leading a 9-person team across front-end, back-end and mobile.

Designed project architecture & approach, lead the technical team, handled BBC technical stakeholders, and passed BBC security & performance audits for a successful release to millions of users.

Ruby, Android, iOS, AWS, Redis, microservices, responsive design.

On-site consultancy - Softwire

October - November 2014

Consultancy, project rescue, security and process analysis.

Tech lead, retail store management tools - Softwire

June 2013 - November 2014

C#, ASP.NET MVC, MSSQL, JavaScript, Knockout.js, Require.js, SASS, Single-Page Apps, remote team.

Tech lead, CouchDB migration - Softwire

December 2012 - June 2013

Designed, pitched and led major update to **Cisco Cloud Web Security** authentication system. System proxied and scanned 50,000 requests per second, on 3,000 servers in 25 data centres, across millions of worldwide daily users.

Successfully live migrated system from per-server storage with RabbitMQ messaging to a distributed CouchDB infrastructure.

Java, Spring, CouchDB, large distributed systems.

Developer, Cisco Cloud Web Security - Softwire

February - December 2012

Worked on-site in agile teams developing security proxy to scan live HTTP(S) traffic for phishing, adware & viruses. Projects included:

- Off-site monitoring platform, to measure real user experience.
 AWS, Python, Puppet, Powershell, Bash, performance testing.
- SAML proxy authentication service. Java, SAML, Spring, Postgres.
- In-memory component test suites to increase test speed and reliability. Java, automated testing, Vertica, HSQLDB, Spring.

Solo developer, SAML auth service - Softwire

January - February 2012

SAML, LDAP, C#, ASP.

Solo developer, RealVNC Blackberry app - Softwire

October - December 2011

Developer internship - Softwire June - September 2010 **Developer internship** - Softwire June - September 2009

Open-source contributions

Open sourced 100% of code written since November 2018.

Created **Lodash**'s initial automated cross-browser testing framework.

Transformed manual deployment into a Docker-based solution for **Staytus.**

Created prebuild infrastructure for **Node's FFI N-API addon** & submodules.

Co-maintainer of React-Autosuggest and Fetch-Mock.

Contributed 31 sets of type definitions & improvements to **DefinitelyTyped**.

Top 10 contributor to projects including JUnit 4, AWS2OpenApi, AdbKit, Sinon.js, Domino, Knockout, and OAS-Kit.

Publications

Hacking Public Services Better
Guest post for the Open Data Institute.

Mockito Essentials Technical reviewer - Packt Publishing

Mockito Cookbook Technical reviewer - Packt Publishing

How To Secure Your Web Stack Published in net magazine #257.

HTTP Toolkit blog: httptoolkit.tech/blog/

Softwire blog: www.softwire.com/blog/author/thp/

Awards

Best in Show - 'Hack The Police' **Twilio Price** - Hackference 2015 **MacRobert Award** - RealVNC project

References available on request.